Finding Aid for Jack Van Coevering Papers 1928-1978
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Jack Van Coevering Papers 1928-1978
Van Coevering, Jack.
21 linear feet
Detroit Free Press outdoor writer and later faculty member in the University of Michigan School of Natural Resources. Files of Detroit Free Press outdoor pages and conservation articles, clippings, and photographs, correspondence, and notes on Michigan conservation history, pesticides, pollution, plants and animals, hunting and fishing, parks, rivers and lakes, conservation writing, and ecology; also manuscript of history of conservation in Michigan with background information; and materials gathered for intended biographical study of Michigan conservationists.
85698 Aa 2
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
The collection was donated by Jack Van Coevering (donor 5729 ) in two accessions, in 1975 and 1978. A subsequent donation of materials given to Frank Angelo (donor 4996 ) by Mrs. Van Coevering was made in 1996.
The collection is open for research.
Jack Van Coevering worked for 35 years as an outdoor writer for the Detroit Free Press. During that time he became noted as an authority on Michigan hunting, fishing, conservation, and other outdoor topics. After his retirement, he taught at the University of Michigan.
John Adrian Van Coevering was born in Grand Haven, Michigan, in 1900. He graduated from the University of Michigan in 1926, and went to work for the Grand Rapids Herald as an outdoor writer. In 1931 Van Coevering moved to Detroit as outdoor writer for the Detroit Free Press. (He was sometimes referred to as the newspaper's outdoor editor.)
Van Coevering worked for the Free Press until he retired in 1965. At the same time he also worked in other media. In 1933 he was editor of a periodical, the Michigan Sportsman. From 1949 to 1953 he hosted a Detroit television program devoted to hunting and fishing in Michigan.
Early in his career, Van Coevering wrote almost exclusively about hunting and fishing, but by the late 1940s he had extended his field of concern to include water pollution. The 1950s saw him writing about pesticides and other environmental concerns, and by the time of his retirement he was interested broadly in environmental problems and the role of the Michigan Department of Natural Resources in combating them.
In the 1967/1968 school year, Van Coevering joined the staff of the University of Michigan School of Natural Resources, first as a research assistant and later as an adjunct professor, teaching outdoor or environmental writing. He worked at the university until late 1974, when he retired and moved to Mesa, Arizona. Van Coevering died in Mesa on May 24, 1978.
As a long-time observer of the Michigan conservation scene, Van Coevering collected a wide range of materials to document the history of hunting, fishing, and wildlife management, the development of state parks and forests, political development of the Department of Conservation and Conservation Commission, concerns about pollution and pesticide poisoning, and other conservation and environmental matters in Michigan. This collection is made up of his writings and background materials on all these topics.
The collection contains only a part of Van Coevering's papers. His "personal" papers were destroyed by his widow after his death. Included here are "historical" papers collected in the course of his work as an outdoor writer. The papers include press releases, clippings, memoranda, reports, and other documents collected by Van Coevering as well as correspondence. Van Coevering's outgoing correspondence is generally of the information-seeking type, and provides little insight into his ideas.
The collection is divided into five major series: Publications, Reference file, School of Natural Resources file, Michigan conservation history file, and Photographs. There is also a small folder of obituaries and other personal information in Box 1. In 1996, the library received an addition to the collection. This 1996 accession from Frank Angelo includes the manuscript of "A Brief History of Conservation in Michigan," and the accompanying research as well as background research for a proposed history of prominent Michigan conservationists.
Subjects:
Birds--Michigan.; Conservation of natural resources--Michigan.; Detroit Free Press.; Detroit River (Mich. and Ont.); Erie, Lake.; Fishes--Michigan.; Fishing--Michigan.; Forests and forestry--Michigan.; Great Lakes.; Hoffmaster, Percy James, 1892-; Hunting--Michigan.; Isle Royale National Park (Mich.); Journalists--Michigan--Detroit.; Lovejoy, Parrish Storrs, 1884-1942.; Mammals--Michigan.; Michigan. Dept. of Conservation.; Michigan. Water Resources Commission.; Natural resources--Michigan.; Parks--Michigan.; Pesticides.; Porcupine Mountains State Park (Mich.); Public lands--Michigan.; Sleeping Bear Dunes National Lakeshore (Mich.); University of Michigan. School of Natural Resources.; Van Coevering, Jack, 1900-; Water pollution.
Subjects - Visual Material:
Camping.; Civilian Conservation Corps (U.S.); Conservation of natural resources--Michigan.; Detroit River (Mich. and Ont.); Fish hatcheries.; Fishing--Michigan.; Forests.; Gillette, Genevieve, 1898-; Hunting--Michigan.; Ponds.; Lakes.; Leonard, Justin W., 1909-1975.; Lighthouses--Michigan.; Michigan. Dept. of Conservation.; Sleeping Bear Dunes (Mich.); Lower Falls (Chippewa County, Mich.); Upper Falls (Luce County, Mich.); Water pollution.; Winter.
Contributors:
Allen, Shirley Walter, 1883-; Bartlett, Ilo H.; Clark, Horace.; Bear, Fred.; Dana, Samuel Trask, 1883-1978; Earle, G. Harold.; East, Ben.; Glassen, Harold W., 1906-; Gunia, Larry.; Harris, William.; Johnson, Carl T.; Lovejoy, Parrish Storrs, 1884-1942.; Millar, C. E. (Charles Ernest), 1885-1955; Pirnie, Miles David, 1898-; Raff, George.; Rahilly, Joseph B.; Ruhl, H. D.; Saunders, Carl M. (Carl Maxon), 1890-1974.; Slater, Kenneth.; Smits, Lee J.; Stephenson, Joe.; Stewart, Gilbert Ireland, 1897-; Stoll, Albert, 1884-; Titus, Harold, 1888-1967.; Westerman, Fred.
Subjects--Sound Recordings
Van Coevering, Jack, 1900-; Conservation of natural resources--Michigan.; University of Michigan. School of Natural Resources.
Contributors--Sound Recordings
Arnold, Keith.
Genre/Form:
Photographs.; Sound recordings.
- Biographical/Personal
  - Obituaries and personal information (Box 1)
- Publications
  The Publications series (Box 1-5) contains scrapbooks of Van Coevering's writings in the Detroit Free Press and other publications, arranged chronologically. Duplicate copies of many of these writings are found under their subjects in the Reference file series.
  - Detroit Free Press"Woods and Waters" column
    - February 1935-December 1946, 7 volumes (Box 1)
    - January 1947-December 1957, 7 volumes (Box 2)
  - Grand Rapids Press and Detroit Times Sunday outdoor page, 1930-1931 (Box 3)
  - Detroit Free Press Sunday outdoor page
    - 1931-1942, 11 folders (Box 3)
    - 1943-1959, 12 folders (Box 4)
      (lacking February 1944-December 1949)
    - 1960-1965, 6 folders (Box 5)
  - Detroit Free Press deer contest, 1936-1964 (Box 5)
  - Detroit Free Press pheasant tally, 1943-1963 (Box 5)
  - Detroit Free Press"Save our Streams" column, 1947-1950 (Box 5)
  - Detroit Free Press"Tips and Tricks" column, 1954-1965 (Box 5)
    (includes index)
  - Detroit Free Press"African Diary" column, 1959 (Box 5)
  - Detroit Dispatch outdoor page, 1967 (Box 5)
  - WUOM Conservation report 1972 (Box 5)
- Reference file
  The Reference file series (Box 5-16) covers the years 1926-1975, although the bulk of the material dates from 1931-1960. This series was created to hold background material for Van Coevering's Free Press column and for his television program. Topics include Michigan hunting- and fishing-related subjects, along with information about Michigan parks and forests. There is also a substantial amount of information about Great Lakes water pollution and pesticide contamination in Michigan. A substantial file relating to the introduction of salmon into the Great Lakes in the 1960s and 1970s postdates the bulk of the material in the series.
  There is considerable overlap among the various headings used in the series. Hunting and fishing material is found both under the headings "Hunting" and "Fishing" and under the names of species, e.g. "Deer" and "Trout." Material about the Michigan Conservation Commission and Department of Conservation is found under headings for those agencies as well as under most of the other topical headings. Material about DDT is found under the heading "Pesticides" and under the names of birds affected, especially "Robin."
  When this series was received from Van Coevering it had been arranged using a very complex classification with many overlapping headings and separate alphabets for "Amphibians and reptiles," "Insects," "Plants," "Birds," "Fish," "Fishing," "Mammals," "Conservation," "Michigan," and "Miscellaneous." In processing, many duplicated headings were consolidated, collected material not related to Michigan conservation was eliminated, and the material was arranged into one alphabet.
  Voluminous correspondence with P. S. Lovejoy appears throughout the Reference file series. Lovejoy seems to have been something of a mentor to Van Coevering and provided him with advice on many topics. Lovejoy's letters may be difficult to identify at first, as they are generally typed on poor quality paper (not letterhead), are usually unsigned, and are usually identified only by the typed initials "PSL" at the beginning or end of the letter. There is also correspondence with H. D. Ruhl, head of the Game Division of the Michigan Department of Conservation (under game-related headings), with archer Fred Bear (under headings relating to bowhunting and deer hunting), with G. Harold Earle of the Wisconsin Land and Lumber Company and Blaney Park resort (under deer- and land use-related headings), and with Carl T. Johnson, member of the Michigan Conservation Commission (under headings relating to the commission and Conservation Department).
  Although little correspondence with outdoor writers Ben East and Albert Stoll is found in the collection, many clippings of their writings are found throughout the Reference file series.
  - Amphibians and reptiles (Box 5)
  - Alewife (Box 5)
  - Au Sable River (Box 5)
  - Bass (Box 5)
  - Bear undated, 1934-1974, 3 folders (Box 6)
  - Beaver (Box 6)
  - Billboards (Box 6)
  - Binoculars (Box 6)
  - Biography (Box 6)
  - Bird surveys undated, 1941-1969, 4 folders (Box 6)
  - Birds, General undated, 1930-1966, 4 folders (Box 6)
  - Birds, Miscellaneous
    - Bittern-Grosbeak (Box 6)
    - Gull-Pigeon (Box 6)
    - Plover-Woodpecker (Box 6)
  - Bluegill (Box 6)
  - Boats and boating undated, 1936-1967, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Bobcat (and other wild cats) (Box 6)
  - Bombing and wildlife (Box 6)
  - Bow hunting undated, 1932-1973, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Bullhead (Box 7)
  - Bunyan, Paul (Box 7)
  - Cabins and camps (Box 7)
  - Calendar of the outdoors, January-December, 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Camping (Box 7)
  - Canoeing (Box 7)
  - Carp (Box 7)
  - Cat (House cat) (Box 7)
  - Christmas trees (Box 7)
  - Civilian Conservation Corps (Box 7)
  - Clam (Mussel) (Box 7)
  - Commercial fishing undated, 1929-1974, 4 folders (Box 7)
  - Conservation and the war (Box 7)
  - Conservation education 1930s-1960s, 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Conservation funding (Box 7)
  - Conservation laws undated, 1930-1970, 5 folders (Box 7)
  - Conservation, Miscellaneous (Box 7)
  - Conservation politics
    - Cutler bill 1933 (Box 7)
    - General (Box 7)
  - Cooking (Box 7)
  - Coyote (Box 8)
  - Crane (Box 8)
  - Crow (Box 8)
  - Dams (Box 8)
  - Dead River (Box 8)
  - Deer undated, 1931-1973, 12 folders (Box 8)
  - Deer kill statistics 1934-1965, 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Detroit River--Harbor line and fill (Box 8)
  - Dog (Box 8)
  - Dog bites--Rabies (Box 8)
  - Drainage (Box 8)
  - Drummond Island (Box 8)
  - Duck undated, 1929-1965, 8 folders (Box 9)
  - Duck decoys (Box 9)
  - Eagle (Box 9)
  - Earthworm (Box 9)
  - Elk (Box 9)
  - Employment, Outdoor (Box 9)
  - Endangered species (Box 9)
  - Esthetics/Ethics (Box 9)
  - Exotic species, General (Box 9)
  - First aid (Box 9)
  - Fish distribution (Creel census) (Box 9)
  - Fish, General undated, 1930-1972, 3 folders (Box 9)
  - Fish, Miscellaneous (Box 9)
  - Fish ponds (Box 9)
  - Fish propagation undated, 1926-1959, 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Fish spearing (Box 9)
  - Fishing, General undated, 1930-1974, 4 folders (Box 10)
  - Fishing--Public access undated, 1932-1970, 4 folders (Box 10)
  - Fishing tackle (including Trout flies) (Box 10)
  - Flowers (Box 10)
  - Foreign travel
    - Africa trip 1959 (Box 10)
    - Colombia safari 1961 (Box 10)
    - Mexican food 1937 (Box 10)
    - Panama fishing 1966 (Box 10)
  - Forest fires (Box 10)
  - Forests and forestry undated, 1930-1965, 3 folders (Box 10)
  - Fox undated, 1929-1949, 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Furs and pelts (Box 10)
  - Game kill statistics (Box 10)
  - Geology (Box 10)
  - Goose (Box 10)
  - Grayling (Box 10)
  - Grouse undated, 1929-1972, 4 folders (Box 11)
  - Guns and ammunition (Box 11)
  - Hawk (Box 11)
  - Herbicides (Box 11)
  - Highway wildlife mortality (Box 11)
  - Hiking (Box 11)
  - Hunting
    - Accidents undated, 1930-1969, 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Hints (Box 11)
    - Private land undated, 1927-1961, 3 folders (Box 11)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 11)
  - Huron-Clinton Metropolitan Authority (Box 11)
  - Huron Mountains (Box 11)
  - Ice fishing undated, 1931-1969, 3 folders (Box 11)
  - Insects (Box 11)
  - Isle Royale 1930-1973, 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Jordan River (Box 11)
  - Lake levels 1933-1965, 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Lakes and rivers, Miscellaneous (Box 11)
  - Lakes--Weed control (Box 11)
  - Lamprey undated, 1924-1970, 4 folders (Box 12)
  - Land and lakes boom (Box 12)
  - Land use (Box 12)
  - Loon (Box 12)
  - Mackinac Island (Box 12)
  - Mammals, General (Box 12)
  - Mammals, Miscellaneous (Box 12)
  - Marten (Box 12)
  - Martiny Lakes (Box 12)
  - Michigan Conservation Commission (Box 12)
  - Michigan counties--History and tourism (Box 12)
  - Michigan Department of Conservation
    - Finance 1931-1971, 2 folders (Box 12)
    - History undated, 1931-1975, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Michigan history, Ancient (Box 12)
  - Mining (Box 12)
  - Mink (Box 12)
  - Minnow (Box 12)
  - Moose (Box 12)
  - Muskegon River--Dam (Box 12)
  - Muskie undated, 1933-1974, 3 folders (Box 12)
  - Muskrat (Box 12)
  - Natural areas (Box 13)
  - Nature centers (Box 13)
  - Ontonagon River--Dam (Box 13)
  - Opossum (Box 13)
  - Otter (Box 13)
  - Outdoor writing (Box 13)
  - Owl (Box 13)
  - Parasites (Box 13)
  - Partridge (Box 13)
  - Pesticides (including DDT) 1945-1971, 4 folders (Box 13)
  - Pheasant undated, 1930-1967, 6 folders (Box 13)
  - Perch (Box 13)
  - Pictured Rocks (Box 13)
  - Pigeon River Country (Box 13)
  - Pike (Northern) (Box 13)
  - Plants, Miscellaneous (Box 13)
  - Point Mouilee (Box 13)
  - Porcupine (Box 13)
  - Porcupine Mountains undated, 1940-1971, 4 folders (Box 13)
  - Predator control (including bounties) undated, 1932-1971, 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Public lands undated, 1931-1971, 3 folders (Box 14)
  - Quail (Box 14)
  - Rabbit undated, 1929-1968, 2 folders (Box 14)
  - Raccoon (Box 14)
  - Resorts
    - Lower Peninsula (Box 14)
    - Upper Peninsula (Box 14)
  - Robin (Box 14)
  - Rural zoning (Box 14)
  - Saginaw Valley flood control (Box 14)
  - St. Clair islands plan (Box 14)
  - Salmon 1935-1974, 5 folders (Box 14)
  - Seney Wildlife Refuge (Box 14)
  - Skiing (Box 14)
  - Skunk (Box 14)
  - Sleeping Bear Dunes (Box 14)
  - Smelt 1931-1968, 2 folders (Box 14)
  - Soil conservation (Box 15)
  - Sportsmen's clubs (Box 15)
  - Spring burning (Box 15)
  - Squirrel (Box 15)
  - State forests (Box 15)
  - State parks (Box 15)
  - Stream improvement undated, 1930-1961, 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Sturgeon (Box 15)
  - Sturgeon River--Dam (Box 15)
  - Tahquamenon Falls (Box 15)
  - Tourism (Box 15)
  - Trees undated, 1928-1970, 4 folders (Box 15)
  - Trout undated, 1928-1972, 7 folders (Box 15)
  - Turkey (Box 15)
  - Vacation pests (Box 15)
  - Walleye (Box 15)
  - Warbler (Box 15)
  - Water pollution
    - Great Lakes 1939-1975, 4 folders (Box 16)
    - Lake Erie (Box 16)
    - Mercury, heavy metals, PCB 1970-1973, 3 folders (Box 16)
  - Water rights (Box 16)
  - Weather (Box 16)
  - Whitefish and cisco (Box 16)
  - Wilderness areas (Box 16)
  - Wolf (Box 16)
  - Wolverine (Box 16)
  - Woodchuck (Box 16)
  - Woodcock (Box 16)
- School of Natural Resources file
  The School of Natural Resources file series (Box 16-17) was created during the period in which Van Coevering taught at the University of Michigan School of Natural Resources, from 1967 to 1974, although the bulk of the material covers the years 1965 to 1970. The series seems to have been created as background for his conservation writing course, but it contains the same sort of material--press releases, clippings, memoranda, reports, and other collected documents--as his earlier files. The topics covered in the most depth in this series are water pollution in the Detroit River and Lake Erie and pesticides, topics also documented in the Reference file series.
  - Bibliography (Box 16)
  - DDT (Box 16)
  - Eastern Michigan Nature Association (Box 16)
  - Environment
    - Attitudes (Box 16)
    - Conservation (Box 16)
    - Education (Box 16)
    - Organizations (Box 16)
  - Hunting and fishing (Box 16)
  - Kniss, Derrell H. (Box 16)
  - Land (Box 16)
  - Nuclear energy (Box 16)
  - Pesticides 1962-1970, 3 folders (Box 16)
  - Poetry (Box 16)
  - Seton, Ernest Thompson (Box 16)
  - Snowshoe Club (Box 16)
  - Teach-in on the Environment 1970 (Box 16)
  - Water pollution--Lake Erie and Detroit River
    - Articles and clippings (Box 17)
    - Conference papers
      - HEW conference, Detroit June 1965 (Box 17)
      - Water Resources Commission conference, Detroit September 1965, 2 folders (Box 17)
      - Law enforcement conference, Detroit November 1965 (Box 17)
      - UAW conference, Detroit November 1965 (Box 17)
      - Michigan Chamber of Commerce conference, Lansing March 1966 (Box 17)
    - Correspondence (Box 17)
    - Technical reports, Miscellaneous (Box 17)
  - Writing about wildlife, by Peter M. Sandman, Jo Ann Myer, James B. Garry (Box 17)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 17)
- Michigan conservation history file
  The Michigan conservation history file series (Box 17-18) was apparently created after Van Coevering moved to Arizona in late 1974. At this time he was working on two books, one a history of conservation in Michigan, the other a series of biographical sketches of conservation leaders in Michigan. The manuscript on the history of conservation in Michigan is located in the 1996 Accession Box 20. The research for the series of biographical sketches can be found in the 1996 Accession Boxes 20-21.
  This series contains correspondence from the 1970s with people active in conservation in Michigan describing their interpretation of various events, press releases and other collected material from the 1970s, and older material probably removed from Van Coevering's Reference file series. There is much overlap between topics in this series and those in the Reference file series, although different headings are sometimes used in the two files. For instance, material on the Collins-Gerhardt or Ne-Bo-Shone case, which established the principle of public access to Michigan streams, is found under the heading "Collins-Gerhardt case (Ne-Bo-Shone case)" in this series and under "Fishing--Public access" in the Reference file series.
  Like the Reference file series, this series also includes correspondence with P. S. Lovejoy, Fred Bear, G. Harold Earle, and Carl T. Johnson.
  - Correspondence and clippings undated, 1940-1978, 9 folders (Box 17)
  - Ames, Floyd V., "Farewell wilderness" (Box 17)
  - Bear, Fred (Box 17)
  - Bibliography (Box 17)
  - Biography (Box 17)
  - Burt Lake State Park--Erosion of public lands (Box 17)
  - Conservation clubs
    - Michigan Audubon Society (Box 17)
    - Michigan Nature Association (Box 17)
    - Michigan United Conservation Clubs (Box 17)
    - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 18)
  - Collins-Gerhardt case (Ne-Bo-Shone case) (Box 18)
  - Detroit News (Box 18)
  - East, Ben (Box 18)
  - Fisheries (Box 18)
  - Fontanna, Stanley G. (Box 18)
  - Gillette, Genevieve (Box 18)
  - Griffith, George (Box 18)
  - Grand Rapids Herald and Press (Box 18)
  - Hazzard, Al (Box 18)
  - Herbert, Paul (Box 18)
  - Hoffmaster, P. J. (Box 18)
  - Houghton, Douglass (Box 18)
  - Johnson, Carl (Box 18)
  - Kitchel Dunes, Grand Haven (Box 18)
  - Lovejoy, P. S. undated, 1932-1975, 4 folders (Box 18)
  - Martiny Lakes (Box 18)
  - Messner, Clarence (Box 18)
  - Media (Box 18)
  - Michigan Department of Conservation
    - Biennial report notes (Box 18)
    - Reorganization 1945-1957, 1963-1964, 4 folders (Box 18)
  - Michigan Department of Natural Resources--Reorganization 1972-1977 (Box 18)
  - Michigan Outdoor Writers Association (Box 18)
  - Mullendore, William J. (Box 18)
  - Neff, Mort (Box 18)
  - Oil and gas (Box 18)
  - Olds, Nicholas (Box 18)
  - Porcupine Mountains (Box 18)
  - Shick, Charles (Box 18)
  - Stace, Arthur (Box 18)
  - State parks (Box 18)
  - Taggart case (Box 18)
  - Wolfe, Joan (Box 18)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 18)
- Photographs
  The Photographs series (Box 19) contains separate subseries of prints and negatives. The photographs cover the period from about 1930 to 1965.
  The prints are generally photos sent to Van Coevering by correspondents or agencies to support "big fish" or "big buck" claims or to document other events. They have been removed from the Reference file series. The negatives were apparently taken by Van Coevering to illustrate his Detroit Free Press columns. The two subseries are arranged for convenience into similar topical groups, but there is no overlap between the two: there are no prints in the prints subseries for any of the negatives and no negatives in the negatives subseries for any of the prints.
  The topics best documented visually in this series include hunting, fishing, related activities such as fly-tying and trapshooting, conservation activities such as fisheries research and forest fire-fighting, and Michigan scenery.
  - Prints
    - Animals (Box 19)
    - Birds (Box 19)
    - Cabins, camping, and resorts (Box 19)
    - Fish and fish culture
      - Stream improvement south of Wolverine on U.S. 27 (Box 19)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 19)
    - Fishing (Box 19)
    - Forests and forest fires (Box 19)
    - Gillette, Genevieve (Box 19)
    - Hunting and trapping (Box 19)
    - Insects (Box 19)
    - Lakes (Box 19)
    - Log jams on Pine River (Lake County) 1933 Ne-Bo-Shone case (Box 19)
    - Lures (Box 19)
    - Mexico (Box 19)
    - Michigan scenes (Box 19)
    - Plants (Box 19)
    - Portraits, Miscellaneous (Box 19)
    - Soil Erosion (Box 19)
    - Trash (Box 19)
    - Van Coevering informal portraits (Box 19)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 19)
  - Negatives: Michigan subjects
    - Cabins, camping, and resorts
      - Bewabic Park, Iron County (Box 19)
        (no. 1-1B)
      - Camping scenes 1962-1963 (Box 19)
        (no. 3-3B)
      - Crystal Downs Resort, Benzie County 1928 (Box 19)
        (no. 5-5A)
      - Lake Valley Resort October 1956 (Box 19)
        (no. 6-6B)
      - Trailers at Grand Rapids August 1935 (Box 19)
        (no. 8-8B)
      - Winter camping scenes (Box 19)
        (no. 9-9E)
    - Farms
      - Bowine Farm 1945 (Box 19)
        (no. 10-10C)
      - James Murphy Farm, Livingston County June 1945 (Box 19)
        (no. 11-11E)
    - Fish and fish culture
      - Bass (Box 19)
        (no. 12)